optimalworkshop.com 2019-05-16

# Privacy Notice | Optimal Workshop

## Privacy Notice

### Who is Optimal Workshop?

Optimal Workshop is a company based in Wellington, New Zealand. For more information about who we are, [read our About Us page](https://www.optimalworkshop.com/about).

NZ Company Number: 1973791  
Email: info@optimalworkshop.com

Our Data Protection Officer (DPO) is [Caroline Carver](mailto:%20privacy@optimalworkshop.com)

### What personal information do we collect?

When you sign up for an account or request a live demonstration, we’ll ask you to provide basic contact information.

When you purchase our services, we’ll ask you to provide basic contact and billing information.

Any optional information is clearly highlighted, and you can utilize our services without providing this information.

This is the personal information that we collect per service:

#### When you contact us via social media

We collect information about your social media handle that you used and the contents of your post or message.

#### When you attend a live demo

When you register for a live demo we collect basic contact information

#### When you email us

We will collect your email address and any contact information provided. We will also collect the contents of your email.

#### When you use our live chat feature

We will collect your contact information, if provided, and the contents of your chat session. If these chats are answered outside of live chat hours, they will be answered via email.

#### When you use our user research platform

When you sign up for our user research platform, we’ll ask you to provide basic contact and billing information. When you utilize the platform we’ll collect information about how you interact with our services and the actions you take, including your IP address.

#### When you sign up for our newsletter or gated content

When you sign up to receive our newsletter or gated content we’ll collect your email address.

#### When you share your story through a case study submission

When you want to share your story with us we’ll collect your email address, company name and details of your story you wish to share.

### When you participate in studies into Optimal’s tool design

When you participate in a study into Optimal’s tool design, we will advise prior to the commencement of the study what information will be collected.

#### Anonymized information

We may collect statistical information about your visit to our website to help us improve it.

### How do we use cookies?

[A cookie](https://www.aboutcookies.org/) is a piece of code that creates a file on your computer to track the pages that you view on our website.

We use cookies for a variety of purposes. Cookies allow browsing and other services offered through our website, and need to be enabled.

Read our [Cookie Policy](https://www.optimalworkshop.com/cookies) to learn more about the cookies we use and what we used them for.

### Why do we collect your personal information?

We collect personal information for some or all of the following reasons to:

  * enable us to provide the services you have subscribed to
  * support capacity planning
  * comply with our legal obligations e.g., tax obligations
  * provide information and marketing materials to you about our services
  * provide gated content that you requested
  * consider hiring you
  * reach out to you to obtain your feedback about our services
  * assist with your support request
  * enable us to identify breaches of our terms and conditions
  * answer your query
  * identify potential customers who may wish to utilize our services

Optimal Workshop does not collect personal information for use by others.

### What legal basis do we have for processing your personal information?

We process your personal information because you’ve given us permission, and we need to process the information to provide the services you have requested and/or to fulfil our contract with you. We may also process your personal information to comply with the law e.g., our tax obligations.

### Who do we share your information with?

We utilize a number of sub processors to enable the provision of services to you. Personal information may be provided to these sub processors as part of delivery of the services. A [list of sub processors](https://support.optimalworkshop.com/hc/en-us/articles/360001267327-Sub-processors-we-use) is available here.

Team owners may request further information regarding the team members’ activities as part of the team. Team owners can’t request a copy of a team member’s activities completed outside of the shared team’s activities.

Anoymised and / or aggregated feedback received as part of a study into Optimal’s tool design may be included in marketing material, blog articles and / or conference presentations.

We do not directly share anonymized information relating to your website usage with any other party. However as detailed within Google’s privacy policy, Google may share this information publicly and with their partners.

We do not disclose your personal information to any third party other than those described previously or when legally mandated.

### How do we secure your information?

Your personal information is held in a controlled and secure environment. We use appropriate technical, organizational and administrative security measures to protect any information we hold from loss, misuse, and unauthorised access, disclosure, alteration and destruction. Among other practices, your account is protected by a password for your privacy and security.

You must prevent unauthorized access to your account by selecting and protecting your password appropriately and limiting access to your computer or device and browser by signing off after you have finished accessing your account.

### Do we use automated decision making or profiling?

We do not use automated decision making or profiling.

### How long do we keep your information?

We only keep your personal information for as long as it is required.

We will keep your personal information:

  * Until we no longer have a valid reason for keeping it
  * Until you request us to stop using it
  * For as long as required by law e.g., we keep invoice information for 7 years to fulfil our tax obligations.

We may keep just enough of your personal information to ensure that we comply with your requests. We will not use your personal information for any purpose other than those  
described in this policy and will comply with your right to deletion.

### Where do we hold your information?

We hold your personal information in the following locations:

  * Amazon Web Services (AWS) in the United States of America
  * Ireland
  * New Zealand

Wherever your information is held we ensure your rights are protected. We do this by:

  * Holding information in Europe and countries with an adequate decision (note New Zealand is one of these)
  * Ensuring we have suitable legal contracts
  * Using sub processors who are members of the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework

### What are your rights?

**Your right** | **How we protect your right**  
---|---  
The right to be informed | We have published this Privacy Notice to keep you informed as to what we do with your personal information. We strive to be transparent about how we use your personal information.  
The right to access | You have the right to access your information. Please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com) if you want to access the personal information we hold about you.  
The right to correction | If the information we hold about you is inaccurate or not complete, you have the right to ask us to rectify it. You can correct your information either within your account or by [emailing us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com).  
The right to deletion | This is sometimes called ‘the right to be forgotten’. If you want us to delete all your personal information please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com).  
The right to restrict processing | You have the right to ask us to restrict how we process your personal information. This means we are permitted to store the data but not further process it. If you want us to restrict processing of your information, please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com).  
The right to data portability | We will allow you to obtain and reuse your personal information for your own purposes across services in a safe and secure way. Please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com) if you wish to port your information.  
The right to object | You have the right to object to how we process your personal information. If you wish to object please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com).  
The right to withdraw consent | If you have given us your consent to process your personal information but change your mind later, you have the right to withdraw your consent at any time. If you want to withdraw your consent, please [email us](mailto:support@optimalworkshop.com).  
The right to complain to a Supervisory Authority | You have the right to complain if you feel that we have not responded to your requests to solve a problem.  
  
### How you can lodge a complaint

There are a few ways to lodge a complaint:

  * With us directly, in writing, to our Data Protection Officer  
PO Box 27546  
Or you can [email our privacy team.](mailto:privacy@optimalworkshop.com)

  * With the New Zealand Office of the Privacy Commissioner.  
Information about how to lodge a complaint is available on the [Privacy Commissioner’s website](http://www.privacy.org.nz/).

  * If you are a European resident you have the right to make a complaint to the Irish Data Protection Commissioner. Information about how to lodge a complaint is available on the [Irish Data Protection Commissioner’s website.](https://www.dataprotection.ie/)

### Will this privacy notice change?

We may change this notice from time to time in the future. Any such changes will be posted here and, where appropriate, notified to you in writing. We advise you to check back frequently to see any updates or changes.
